Guide to the Records of the 7th Regiment 1767-1983 (bulk 1830-1947) MS 556
New-York Historical Society
- Series XIV: Visual Materials, 1806-1983, 12104
  - Visual Materials--Oversize, 12164
    - "Romance in the Holy Land"--Poster, Undated; 12165 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Posters, 12157
    - World War I Posters U.S.: War Stamps and Bonds, Liberty Loan, Red Cross, Recruitment Posters (Marines, Navy), United War Work Campaign (including one from the American Library Assn.), and posters to encourage businesses to hire returning soldiers., 1917-1919, undated; 12163 (Box 75)
    - World War I Posters One of the posters is British, made from canvas, that 'advertises' the British Red Cross Society and the Order of St. John Enquiry Department for Wounded and Missing. All the rest are US, including War Bonds, Liberty Bonds, Red Cross, Army and Navy Recruitment. There are five poster 'portraits', dated 1918, from The New York Herald - Magazine of the War., 1917-1918, undated; 12162 (Box 76)
    - World War I Posters Includes European posters (German, French, British, Scottish) focusing on recruitment and solicitation. The remaining 31 posters are U.S., including six poster "portraits', dated 1918, from The New York Herald - Magazine of the War; Liberty Loan (including one from the Boy Scouts of America), Buy Bonds, Red Cross solicitations (including one Red Cross Christmas Roll Call), and American Field Service., 1917-1918, undated; 12161 (Box 77)
    - World War I Posters Three posters: "Come On!", "And They Thought We Couldn't Fight," and "Order of Battle Hindenburg Line September 29, 1918.", 1918, undated; 12160 (Box 78)
    - Civil War Posters and Grenade Blueprints Depiction of 1863-1864 Civil War Battles, 1887-1893, 1938, undated; 12159 (Box 79)
    - War Department Illustrated Reference Posters, 1943-1945; 12158 (Box 80)
  - Lantern Slides, 12153
    - Glass Lantern Slides--Mexican Border, McAllen, TX, 1916; 12156 (Box 81)
    - Glass Lantern Slides--Identified and Unidentified Soldiers and Camp Life, Undated; 12155 (Box 82)
    - Glass Lantern Slides--Identified and Unidentified Soldiers and Camp Life, Undated; 12154 (Box 83)
  - Volumes, 12131
    - Photograph Album--"Thirty-three War Time 1861-3 Photographs Sixth Co. 7th Regiment", 1861-1863; 12152 (Volume 397)
    - Photograph Album, [1862]; 12151 (Volume 398)
    - Photograph Album--Fourth Co., Portraits, 1864; 12150 (Volume 399)
    - "Scrapbook"--Col. Emmons Clark Retirement, 1884; 12149 (Volume 400)
    - Photograph Album--"7th Regiment NGSNY State Camp", 1889; 12148 (Volume 401)
    - Scrapbook with Photographs-- Gettysburg, Camp Smith, 1896-1916; 12147 (Volume 402)
    - Photograph Album--Croton Dam, 1900; 12146 (Volume 403)
    - Photograph Album--Queen's Westminster Volunteers match, 1905; 12145 (Volume 404)
    - Photograph Album-- Peekskill, 1911; 12144 (Volume 405)
    - "Les Armees de L'est Mars-Avril 1915"-- Prints of charcoal and pencil sketches (mostly portraits of French officers), 12143 (Volume 406)
    - "Verdun Mars-Avril 1916"--Prints of charcoal and pencil sketches (landscapes and portraits), 12142 (Volume 407)
    - "Roll of Honor 1917-1918 World War I Dead"--Lists of Burial Locations and Copies of Photographs, Undated; 12141 (Volume 408)
    - Scrapbook of Photos--Parade of Active 7th Regiment and Veterans in NYC, 1919; 12140 (Volume 409)
    - Photograph Album--Portraits, 7th Regiment, Undated; 12139 (Volume 410)
    - Photograph Album--Camp Smith, Peekskill, Undated; 12138 (Volume 411)
    - Photograph Album, Undated; 12137 (Volume 412)
    - Photograph Album, Undated; 12136 (Volume 413)
    - Photograph Album--"DeWitt Clinton Falls Photograph Album Vol. 1", Undated; 12135 (Volume 414)
    - Photograph Album-- "DeWitt Clinton Falls Photograph Album Vol. 2", Undated; 12134 (Volume 415)
    - Photograph Album-- "DeWitt Clinton Falls Photograph Album Vol. 3", 1908-1909; 12133 (Volume 416)
    - Scrapbook with Photographs--"D.W.C. Falls Photograph Album Vol. IV Texas 1916", 12132 (Volume 417)
  - Oversize Volumes, 12116
    - Photograph Album--"107th Infantry 27th Division 1921," Peekskill, 12130 (Volume 418)
    - Etchings--"Life Studies of the Great Army", 12129 (Volume 419)
    - Photograph Album, 1886; 12128 (Volume 420)
    - Photograph Album--"Events and Places Concerning Gen. D.C. Falls", 1861-1898; 12127 (Volume 421)
    - Water Color-- "Camp Sites at the Outbreak of the Civil War By L. N. Rosenthal 1862", 12126 (Volume 422)
    - Prints of Drawings-- "Regimental Types at Creedmoor Drawn by George Gibson 1882", 12125 (Volume 423)
    - Extra Illustrated Volume--"A Tribute to the Seventh Regiment", 1871; 12124 (Volume 424)
    - Photo Album--Daniel Appleton, Undated; 12123 (Volume 425)
    - Photo Album--Camp Sherman, Saratoga, 1872; 12122 (Volume 426)
    - Scrapbook with Photographs--Camp Smith, 1931; 12121 (Volume 427)
    - Photo Album--"Souvenir 7th Regiment Centennial Camp to Col. Emmons Clark by G. W. Pach" (housed in box), 1876; 12120 (Volume 428)
    - Photo Album--Camp of '93, Volume I, 1893; 12119 (Volume 429)
    - Photo Album--Camp of '93, Volume II, 1893; 12118 (Volume 430)
    - Photo Album--Camp of '93, Volume III, 1893; 12117 (Volume 431)
  - Items, 12105
    - "First Troop National Guard" (framed), 1838-1846; 12115 (Box Item, Folder #1)
    - Col. Daniel Appleton--Portrait (framed), Undated; 12114 (Box Item, Folder #2)
    - New York State Militia Uniforms--16 color plates of military uniforms (in enclosure), 1853-1858, undated; 12113 (Box Item, Folder #3)
    - Daguerreotype--Former Colonel of the 7th Regiment--Unidentified (in enclosure), Undated; 12112 (Box Item, Folder #4)
    - Glass Plate Negative--"Col. Tobin - Prince of Wales Picture" (in enclosure), 1919; 12111 (Box Item, Folder #5)
    - Ordnance Survey Photograph--"The Spoil Bank of the Bellicourt Tunnel, as seen from BONY" at the Hindenburg Line, 1920; 12110 (Box Item, Folder #6)
    - Recruitment Poster "A Call to Arms" British WWI, Undated; 12109 (Box Item, Folder #7)
    - Color Poster "Lend the way they Fight" WWI, Undated; 12108 (Box Item, Folder #8)
    - Canvas-backed Recruiting Posters (4), Undated; 12107 (Box Item, Folder #9)
    - Japanese Instrument of Surrender ending WWII (reproduction), 1945; 12106 (Box Item, Folder #10)
- Series XV: Maps, 1912-1948, 12101
  This series includes maps used for military training and maneuvers in the U.S., and maps depicting European campaigns and events of World War I. Most of the maps are topographical and strategic; some training maps have markings, many of the World War I maps are labeled.
  - U.S.--Training, Maneuvers, 1912-1948, undated; 12103 (Box 84)
  - Europe--World War I, 1914-1918; 12102 (Box 85)
- Series XVI: Artifacts, 1806-1961, 12069
  This series contains artifacts of the 7th Regiment. It includes many ribbons, pins, and flags. It also includes other items such as dog tags, games, and a booklet on the project to catalog the items in the 7th Regiment library.
  - Printed Label on Cardboard reading "1806 Masonic Artillerie Company Second Company Company B Seventh Regiment N.Y.S.M.", 12100 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Regimental Fair Souvenirs (ticket, illustrated card, ladies badges, guns and target pin, subscriptions for prizes, and ribbons), 1879; 12099 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Grant Memorabilia (pamphlet, ribbons, envelope), 1885, 1897, undated; 12098 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Watch Fobs, 1909, 1916; 12097 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Mexican Border Seal and Rifle Marksman's Badge, 1916, undated; 12096 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Army Orders - Awards for Gallantry and Devotion to Duty in Action, 1919; 12095 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Locker Tabs, Undated; 12094 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - 7th Regiment Crests, Undated; 12093 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Mementos of Colonel Ellsworth, Undated; 12092 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Hat Bands and Glove, Undated; 12091 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Veterans of the Seventh Regiment commemorative coin, Undated (Box 89, Folder 11)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Acquired June 11, 2018 (accession no. MS.2018.025).
  - Red White and Blue Rosette worn by many prisoners in Libby Prison, 1862; 12090 (Box 90)
  - Wooden Soldier with note of explanation written by D.W.C. Falls, 1914; 12089 (Box 90)
  - Booklet describing WPA project to conserve and catalog contents of the military library of the 107th Infantry Regiment, 1940; 12088 (Box 91)
  - Index Cards of names and addresses, Undated; 12087 (Box 91)
  - Ribbons (6), 1874, 1892, 1916, undated; 12086 (Box 92)
  - Dog Tags of George Darling (Pvt. 1st Cl Btry. D 394 F.A.), Undated; 12085 (Box 92)
  - Pins (5), Undated; 12084 (Box 92)
  - Shoulder Straps (2), Undated; 12083 (Box 92)
  - Ribbons, 1874-1916, undated; 12082 (Box 93)
  - Pins, Paperweight, and Small Container, 1879-1917, undated; 12081 (Box 93)
  - Playing Cards and a Cribbage Board and Cribbage Pieces in a container to appear like a 7th Regiment backpack, Undated; 12080 (Box 94)
  - Box of Mapping Tools, Undated; 12079 (Box 94)
  - Medals, 1884-1905; 12078 (Box 94)
  - Four Flags, Undated; 12077 (Box 95)
  - War Games Set, Undated; 12076 (Box 95)
  - Sign reading "Seventh Regiment", Undated; 12075 (Box 95)
  - Framed Set of Pins and Medals, 1885-1898; 12074 (Box 96)
  - Helmet, Undated; 12073 (Box 96)
  - Hat with 7th Regiment Insignia, Undated; 12072 (Box 96)
  - Tube containing Proclamations for Seventh Regiment Day and Seventh Regiment Week, 1956, 1961; 12071 (Box 96)
  - Fragments and Artifact Housing, 12070 (Box 97)
- Labels and Envelopes, 12065
  Handwritten labels and envelopes found loose in collection.
  - Labels, 12068 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Labels, 12067 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Alienated Envelopes, 12066 (Box 42, Folder 5)